



# **Tom Phan**

Hayward, CA 925-404-9999 tomtldr@gmail.com

Experienced Senior Frontend Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in Startup & Enterprise Web and Mobile Applications. Actively searching for a challenging position that not only encourages self-learning and a collaborative learning / teaching environment but also pushes for challenging results driven projects.

## **Work Experience**



#### **Technical Lead**

06/2020 to 11/2023

Avail Medsystems Santa Clara, CA

- · Lead 5 Core Projects
  - Browser (React.js, TypeScript, Redux): scheduling and managing calls + events, internationalization, and realtime notifications
  - Browser (React.js, TypeScript, Redux): video conferencing, PubNub and Splunk integration
  - Mobile (React Native): worked on creating an Avail App for iPhone / Android
  - Proprietary Pubnub Library (Twilio + Node): custom librhelped Remote Clients, Console, and Backend interact
  - Console (Swift): core application for company product, integrated video conferencing with remote clients
- Delivered high performant, reusable UI Components and Microframeworks
- Managed JIRA board to update and delegate tasks and trained Junior to Senior Engineers
- Trained and mentored Junior to Senior Engineers

#### **Lead Frontend Developer**

09/2019 to 05/2020

Sofar Ocean

San Francisco, CA

- Developed the SPA Weather Dashboard in React, Redux, Material UI, and TypeScript
- Dashboard handles ~100,000 Data Points in multiple Charts w/ little impact to performance
- Implemented Style Guidelines for future Sofar Projects
- · Maintained old Angular 1 Spotter Dashboard

#### Software Developer II

06/2018 to 09/2019

Oracle

Redwood Shores, CA

- Design, developed, and implemented reusable JET Components and Single Page Applications for over 1000 Oracle Engineers using React.js and Redux
- Maintain React-based & Sites and Applications for Oracle Subsidiaries and Acquisitions until migration to JET
- Create Selenium and Unit tests on each application/feature to ensure longevity of code using Python
- Adhere to Agile process to iteratively roll out new features and update existing projects

#### **Frontend Developer**

11/2016 to 06/2018

Kaiser Permanente

Oakland, CA

- Built Internal Kaiser Permanente platform SPA in React.s & Redux
- Maintained Site for over 600 Executives, Directors, Administrators, and Managers
- Migrated ES5 to ES6, Angular 1 to React 16
- Migrated .NET to Django
- Built script/automation tools in Python
- Monitored Site Data & Metrics via Google Analytics, Tableau, and Excel

### **Teaching Associate**

08/2014 to 06/2016

California State University, East Bay

Hayward, CA

Created lesson plans, numerous learning techniques, and strategically formulated problems that challenged students to not memorize but learn the mathematical applications of theories and formulas

- 99% Overall Pass Rate on Final Department Exam
- 100% Retention Rate for Sequenced Courses

## **Skills**



JavaScript, HTML, CSS - 7 years

React.js - 6 years

React Native, TypeScript, Next.js - 3 years

Node.js, Python, Django - 2 years

#### **Education**



# California State University, East Bay

Master's Applied Mathematics Hayward, CA 09/2014 to 06/2016

# University of California, Santa Barbara

Bachelor's Mathematics Santa Barbara, CA 09/2010 to 06/2013